# **Tim Carlock**

New York, NY

timothy.carlock@gmail.com http://linkedin.com/in/tscarlock http://timcarlock.com https://github.com/tcarlock

I have over 15 years of engineering and product-development experience, with a particular interest in organizational design, product strategy and user experience. I have sector experience in financial services, consumer tech and business software. I co-founded a software startup where I managed product strategy and development, and I was an early(ish) employee at Uber.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Fast | New York, NY

Senior Engineering Manager - Sellers, Affiliates & FE Platform, Sept 2021 - April 2022

Fast was an eCommerce startup building one-click checkout for merchants to sell both online and in the physical world. I built and ran an organization of  $^{\sim}20$  engineers reporting to 3 engineering managers (my direct reports). My organization consisted of three cross-functional, product-engineering teams (Seller Onboarding, Seller Dashboard and Affiliate), as well as the Web Platform team.

- Moved the product-eng teams away from being front-end focused in order to reduce organizational coupling/blockers and establish better ownership for domain-specific services and endpoints.
- Hired managers and engineers, supported and coached engineers and managers and provided mentoring to a first-time manager.
- Worked regularly with Product, Design and Data Science leads to create and maintain an organizational strategy, assess team trajectory/impact and streamline project execution.

# Better.com | New York, NY

Senior Engineering Manager - Sellers, Affiliates & FE Platform, Nov 2020 - Jun 2021

I built and ran the Customer Service Experience (CSE) organization consisting of ~30 engineers reporting to 3 engineering managers (my direct reports). The CSE org consisted of four teams: Comms Platform, Comms Compliance, Issue Resolution and Growth.

- Reorganized and rechartered the Comms teams to better balance staffing and workload across the teams and provide more-clear ownership of projects and services.
- Worked closely with Product to overhaul the org strategy around Comms and define new charters/roadmaps for each sub-team.
- Mentored engineers and managers, including a first-time manager.
- Worked with recruiting to overhaul key elements of the hiring framework/process. Primarily, this included
  articulating a hiring philosophy, improving definition of and training for the module-owner and bar-raiser
  programs and implementing a pair-programming module for onsite interviews.
- Designed and implemented a checkpoint framework for program management to improve team alignment and provide functional teams with greater visibility and foresight.

## Uber | San Francisco, CA & New York, NY

Engineering Manager - Eats - Restaurant Acquisition, Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

The Acquisition organization focused on the top-of-funnel and early-lifecycle portion of the Eats experience for restaurants, and was responsible for increasing the number of active restaurants in the Eats network. The organization consisted of three teams: Registration, Onboarding and Leads Platform. I started and directly managed the Registration and Leads Platform teams, and supported a first-time manager who was responsible for Onboarding.

Engineering Manager - Developer Experience - Uber Studio, Mar 2017 - Jan 2019

I built and ran the Studio organization which was responsible for the tools and platform used by both engineers and ops to test and simulate the production experience across a variety of Uber products including Eats and Rides. Studio allowed users to create test accounts, mock riders and drivers and simulate rides and deliveries in any region under a variety of conditions (e.g., multiple riders, ride cancellations, etc) using a web or mobile client. The organization consisted of ~15 engineers and three core teams: Cerberus (network routing), Studio Platform and Tooling. I built the product organization from the ground up and absorbed the networking team as part of a strategy shift.

# Senior Engineer & Tech Lead - Uber for Business, May 2014 - May 2016

I was a tech lead for the engineering team that originally built and launched Uber for Business. As Senior Engineer and Tech Lead I helped build and run the team that owned the web dashboard used to manage rider accounts, invoices and payments and ride policies. Following the initial launch, I ran the effort to migrate from Backbone to React, and I helped introduce React as the standard across the web teams. I started and ran the web guild which was responsible for knowledge sharing and setting standards for web development across the company.

## Learnist | San Francisco, CA

Senior Engineer, Feb 2013 - May 2014

Learnist was a group-based content and skill sharing platform. I was a full-stack engineer and the tech lead for the team that owned the web application. In addition to building and launching new features, this team was responsible for migrating from server-rendered views in Ruby on Rails to a single-page application built using Angular.

# Expedia | San Francisco, CA

Senior Engineer, Feb 2013 - May 2014

I was on the new social content team and contributed to a service that collected, stored and and served user-generated reviews for hotels and other properties. This high-availability API was accessed by dozens of other services that powered various Expedia Group sites. The service was built with Java/Spring and MongoDB.

## Nexly | St Louis, MO

Co-Founder & Product Lead, Aug 2009 - Apr 2012

Nexly was a SAAS product which provided outsourced procurement for SMBs. Specifically, we provided data, tools and services that allowed businesses to find, assess and select vendors for IT services including email, server co-location and data retention/recovery. I was responsible for market and user research, product strategy and product design/implementation.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Missouri - St. Louis, MO

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems, Aug 2004

Coursework in system architecture, relational databases, OOP/language design and project management.

## University of Missouri - St. Louis, MO

Bachelor of Science in Finance, Jan 2003

Coursework in asset pricing, portfolio allocation, corporate finance, economic modeling and accounting.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

 $\textbf{Languages:} \ \mathsf{JavaScript}, \ \mathsf{Ruby}, \ \mathsf{Java}, \ \mathsf{C\#}, \ \mathsf{SQL}, \ \mathsf{HTML}, \ \mathsf{CSS/Sass}$ 

Frameworks/Libraries: React/ReactNative, Redux, NextJS, Ruby

on Rails

Tools: Confluence, Jira, Phabricator, Git, WebPack, Jenkins,

Figma, Sketch